# **Duc Hieu Pham**

Software Engineer at Facebook

# Summary

A computer enthusiast, Duc Hieu loves to program and builds software. Duc Hieu has experience in building applications in Java and C++. Duc Hieu plans to pursue distributed systems in college.

Duc Hieu lived in Singapore for 4 years to pursue his high school education, and currently is pursuing a degree in Computer Science in University of Illinois, Urbana - Champaign. He loves reading about math, science, economics and politics.

# Experience

### Software Engineer at Facebook

February 2016 - Present

Search Ranking Infrastructure Search-as-a-Service

Works mainly on C++. Making search engine more scalable and reliable.

#### Software Engineer Intern at Facebook

May 2015 - August 2015 (4 months)

ODS Monitoring, Data Infrastructure

#### Software Engineer Intern at Microsoft

January 2015 - April 2015 (4 months)

Data and Fundamentals, OS Core.

#### **Software Engineer Intern at Google**

May 2014 - August 2014 (4 months)

Worked to improve reliability of MySQL

#### Software Engineer Intern at John Deere

September 2013 - December 2013 (4 months)

Worked on iOS applications that assist John Deere agricultural equipments.

Employed various APIs, such as Yahoo Weather, Yahoo Geocoding and Google Maps

## Education

## University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science, 2012 - 2016

**Activities and Societies:** Association for Computing Machinery

**St Andrew's Junior College** GCE A Level, 2010 - 2011

Activities and Societies: Environment Club, Mcnair Hostel Committee

**Anglo - Chinese School (Independent)** 

GCE O Level, 2008 - 2009

Activities and Societies: Mathematics Competition Team, Environment Focus Group

**National University of Singapore** 

Mathematics, 2011 - 2011

**Singapore Management University** 

Economics, 2011 - 2011

## Honors and Awards

Singapore Mathematical Olympiad (Open Section), Singapore Mathematical Olympiad (Senior Section), Service Award, Honor's Day Award, Commendation Award

# **Duc Hieu Pham**

Software Engineer at Facebook



Contact Duc Hieu on LinkedIn